Guide to the Phyllis Chesler Papers, 1968-2003 RL.00221
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal and Professional Papers Series
  - People Files subseries, ca. 1970-1989 (bulk 1970-1979)
    The People Files Subseries, ca. 1970-1989 (chiefly 1970s), contains correspondence, clippings, notes, and other miscellaneous materials related to individuals and institutions with whom and which Chesler was in contact during this period. Much of the material in the series documents Chesler's personal and professional concerns following the publication of Women, Money and Power and prior to publication of About Men and With Child, with a particular emphasis on her relationships with other feminist writers and activists. The folders are arranged by last name, except for the small number where Chesler's original folder title referred to an institution. These files are interfiled within the established alphabetical order, maintaining Chesler's original order.
    - Abou - Saif, Laila (Box P/P7)
    - Abzug, Bella (Box P/P7)
    - Abzug - Campaign Lit. (Box P/P7)
    - Adams, Margaret (Box P/P7)
    - Alda, Alan (Box P/P7)
    - Alpert, Rabbi Rebecca (Box P/P7)
    - Alpert, Jane -- Petitions, 1975 (Box P/P7)
    - Alta (Box P/P7)
    - Anna-Kria (Box P/P7)
    - Angell. Ferolyn (Box P/P7)
    - Apuzzo, Gimmy (Box P/P7)
    - Arieti, Silvano (Box P/P7)
    - Arnold, June (Box P/P7)
    - Atkinson, Ti-Grace (Box P/P7)
    - Baker, Dawn (Box P/P7)
    - Baker, Jill (Box P/P7)
    - Baker-Miller, Jean (Box P/P7)
    - Baraheni, Reza (Box P/P7)
    - Barber, Ted (Box P/P7)
    - Bart, Pauline (Box P/P7)
    - Bazin, Danielle - I.N.S.T.R.A.W. (Box P/P7)
    - Bell, Carolyn Shaw - Money Book (Box P/P7)
    - Bellamy, Carol - Senator (Box P/P7)
    - Belzberg, Leslie - general (Box P/P7)
    - Bergmann - Video Agreement (Box P/P7)
    - Berkman, Ted (Box P/P7)
    - Bernardy-Bonnesatti, Jeresa (Box P/P7)
    - Bernikow, Louise (Box P/P7)
    - Bernstein, Maxine (Box P/P7)
    - Bing, Elisabeth (Box P/P7)
    - Birnbaum, Norman (Box P/P7)
    - Bolesky, Karen (Box P/P7)
    - Bolotin, Judy - Random House (Box P/P7)
    - Bonder, Gloria (Box P/P7)
    - Boyle, Margaret (Box P/P7)
    - Boyle, Peggy (Box P/P7)
    - Branden, Nathaniel (Box P/P7)
    - Brogger, Suzanne (Box P/P7)
    - Broner, Esther - 1978-1979 (Box P/P7)
    - Broner, Esther - Publishing trouble, Fall 1975 (Box P/P7)
    - Broner, Sari (Box P/P7)
    - Bronshtien, Nachmy (Box P/P7)
    - Bronshtien, Nachmy - Immigration and English lessons (Box P/P7)
    - Bronshtien, Nachmy - Social security (Box P/P7)
    - Bronte, Lydia - 1980 (Box P/P7)
    - Brown, Jerry (Box P/P7)
    - Brown, Penny (Box P/P7)
    - Brown, Rit Mae (Box P/P7)
    - Brown-Miller, Susan (Box P/P7)
    - Budapest, Zee (Box P/P7)
    - Burke, France (Box P/P7)
    - Burland, Joyce (Box P/P7)
    - Burnstein, Karen (Box P/P7)
    - B - Miscellaneous (Box P/P7)
    - Calesky, Reva (Box P/P7)
    - Capello, Phyllis (Box P/P7)
    - Carp, Robert (Box P/P7)
    - Catalyst - Felice Schwartz, Pres. (Box P/P7)
    - Cebellos, Jacqueline (Box P/P7)
    - Chabaku, Motalepula (Box P/P7)
    - Chadorow, Nancy (Box P/P7)
    - Chadwick, Whitney (Box P/P7)
    - Chalfi, Rahel (Box P/P7)
    - Chasen, Barbara (Box P/P7)
    - Chesler, Jack (Box P/P7)
    - Chesler, Norman (Box P/P7)
    - Chicago, Judy (Box P/P7)
    - Christmas, June (Box P/P7)
    - Clarke, Libby (Box P/P7)
    - Clayton, Jay (Box P/P7)
    - Collins, Judy - Atonia film (Box P/P7)
    - Collins, Pat (Box P/P7)
    - Cook, Cynthia (Box P/P7)
    - Cooperman, Mira Hammermesh (Box P/P7)
    - Covey, Sue (Box P/P7)
    - Cowan, Belita (Box P/P7)
    - Cunningham, Gloria (Box P/P7)
    - Curtiss, Lucie (Box P/P7)
    - C - Miscellaneous. (Box P/P7)
    - Daniels, Rosemary (Box P/P7)
    - Davis, Dr. Eugene (Box P/P7)
    - Deitch, Donna - Desert Heart (Box P/P7)
    - Deming, Barbara (Box P/P7)
    - Denmark, Florence (Box P/P7)
    - Densen-Gerber, Judianne (Box P/P7)
    - De Ponte, Laura - general (Box P/P7)
    - De Ponte, Laur-oh - (notes, etc.) (Box P/P7)
    - Dershowitz, Alan (Box P/P7)
    - Dinnerstein, Dorothy (Box P/P7)
    - Divi, Nuria (Box P/P7)
    - Dodson, Betty - Correspondence (Box P/P7)
    - Dolen, Arnold (Box P/P7)
    - Dolen, Arnold - 1979 (Box P/P7)
    - Dorrance & Company, Inc. (Box P/P7)
    - Dreifus, Claudia (Box P/P7)
    - Duchin, Linda (Box P/P7)
    - Duncan, Erika (Box P/P7)
    - Dworkin, Andrea (Box P/P7)
    - East Hampton: sale of home - Edward Horne (Atty) (Box P/P7)
    - Edelman, Lily (Box P/P7)
    - Eisenberg, Janie (Box P/P7)
    - Elkin, Sandy (woman) (Box P/P7)
    - Endervelt, Jeff (Box P/P7)
    - Engelson, Joyce (Box P/P7)
    - Engler, Lily M.D. (Box P/P7)
    - Epstein, Mel (Box P/P7)
    - Erickson, Nancy (Box P/P7)
    - Eshel, Tamak (Box P/P7)
    - Espin, Olivia (Box P/P7)
    - Farrell, Warren - Lib. man (Box P/P7)
    - Feigen-Fasteau, Brenda, Mark, and Alix (Box P/P7)
    - Fellechner, Uta (Box P/P7)
    - Fiddler -- closing (Box P/P7)
    - Fiddler - invoice (Box P/P7)
    - Fielden, Sandra (Box P/P7)
    - Fischer, Stacey J. (Box P/P7)
    - Flakes, Susan (Box P/P7)
    - Frankfurt, Ellen (Box P/P7)
    - Freeman, Jo (Box P/P7)
    - Friedan, Betty (Box P/P7)
    - Fritz, Leah (Box P/P7)
    - Gaffinkel, Carolyn (Box P/P7)
    - Garbus, Martin (Box P/P7)
    - Garcia, Inez (Box P/P7)
    - Garcia, Sandy (Box P/P7)
    - Gibel, Inge Lederer (Box P/P7)
    - Giraq, Rebecca (Box P/P7)
    - Glenwick, David (Box P/P7)
    - Gorewitz, Rubin (Box P/P7)
    - Gorin, Frank (Box P/P7)
    - Gorra, Georgine (Box P/P7)
    - Gorra, Georgine (Box P/P7)
    - Gottlieb, Bob (Box P/P7)
    - Goulianos, Joan (Box P/P7)
    - Green, Richard (Box P/P7)
    - Green, Richard (Box P/P7)
    - Greenbaum, Woulfe, Ernst (Box P/P7)
    - Greenfield, Gloria Z. - Pomegranate Productions (Box P/P7)
    - Griffen, Grace (Box P/P7)
    - Griffen, Susan (Box P/P7)
    - Grosberg, Carol (Box P/P7)
    - Gross, Helene (Box P/P7)
    - Guessous, Azeddin - Morocco (Box P/P7)
    - Guggenheimer, Elinor (Box P/P7)
    - Guthrie, Lee (Box P/P7)
    - Gutman, Jeremiah (Box P/P7)
    - Gutman, Rita (Box P/P7)
    - Guttman, Elaine (Box P/P7)
    - Hakim, Ellie (Box P/P7)
    - Hawkins, John (Box P/P7)
    - Hargiss, Nancy (Box P/P7)
    - Harris, Bertha (Box P/P7)
    - Harrison, Lewis (Box P/P7)
    - Haskell, Molly (Box P/P7)
    - Havas, Eva (Box P/P7)
    - Hawkins, John (Box P/P7)
    - Hazleton, Leslie (Box P/P7)
    - Head, Mrs. Peter - "Orange Boy" (Box P/P7)
    - Heimann, Sosh (Box P/P7)
    - Hemmermesh, Mira (Box P/P7)
    - Henley, Nancy (Box P/P7)
    - Henry, Sherry (Box P/P7)
    - Herman, Judy (Box P/P7)
    - Hermus, Gary Paul (Box P/P7)
    - Hirsch, Lolly (Box P/P7)
    - Hite, Shere (Box P/P7)
    - Hope, Judith (Box P/P7)
    - House Keepers (Box P/P7)
    - Howard, Marion (Box P/P7)
    - Howell, Mary (Box P/P8)
    - Huber, Sherry (Box P/P8)
    - Identity House (Box P/P8)
    - Jacobs, Karen (Box P/P8)
    - Jacobs, Karen Folger (Box P/P8)
    - Jacobs, Rhoda (Box P/P8)
    - Jakab, Elizabeth (Box P/P8)
    - Johnson, Eleanor (Box P/P8)
    - Johnson, Sonia (Box P/P8)
    - Jong, Erica (Box P/P8)
    - Jong, Erica - baby shower (Box P/P8)
    - Juengert, Laurie (Box P/P8)
    - Kantaroff, Maryon (Box P/P8)
    - Kaplan, Sheila - C.U.N.Y. (Box P/P8)
    - Karp, Lila (Box P/P8)
    - Kawano, Kiyomi (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Joan Gadol (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Mary (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Mary - Agreement with Richard (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Mary - Money for Women (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Mary - Real Estate (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Mary - Separation Agreement (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Mary - Will (Box P/P8)
    - Kelly, Ray (Box P/P8)
    - Kenworthy, Joy Anne (Box P/P8)
    - Keraga, Taiwo (Box P/P8)
    - Kessler, Winnefred (Box P/P8)
    - Khairzada, Faiz (Box P/P8)
    - Kimball, Linda Musmeci (Box P/P8)
    - Kingsley, Joan (Box P/P8)
    - Kreloff, Bea (Box P/P8)
    - Krupsack, Mary Anne (Box P/P8)
    - Langer, Edith J., M.D. (Box P/P8)
    - Leavitt, Ruby Rohrlich (Box P/P8)
    - Lederer, Laura (Box P/P8)
    - Lee, Martin A. (Box P/P8)
    - Leitner, Isabella (Box P/P8)
    - Lerman, Rhoda (Box P/P8)
    - Levine, Selma (Box P/P8)
    - Levy, Marilyn (Box P/P8)
    - Liehm, A.J. - Richmond, 1976 (Box P/P8)
    - Lifshin, Lyn (Box P/P8)
    - Lim, Aldaba (Box P/P8)
    - Lippard, Lucy (Box P/P8)
    - Loomis, Gloria (Box P/P8)
    - Lorde, Audre (Box P/P8)
    - Maddi, Dr. Salvator (Box P/P8)
    - Mandel, Tina (Box P/P8)
    - Marcos de Robert, Sylvia (Box P/P8)
    - Marcus, Helen (Box P/P8)
    - Markson, Elaine (Box P/P8)
    - Marshall, Janet Chase (Box P/P8)
    - Mary King Assoc. Inc. (Box P/P8)
    - Matthews, Diane (Box P/P8)
    - Mayo, Anna (Box P/P8)
    - Mazow, Julia Wolf (Box P/P8)
    - McAddams, Cynthia (Box P/P8)
    - McBride, Angela (Box P/P8)
    - McFadden, Cyra (Box P/P8)
    - McMullin, David (Box P/P8)
    - Mead - Chesler Dialogue (Box P/P8)
    - Mead, Margaret (Box P/P8)
    - Merians-Grossman, Helene (Box P/P8)
    - Messana, Ida (Box P/P8)
    - Miller, George (Box P/P8)
    - Millet, Kate (Box P/P8)
    - Moore, Honor (Box P/P8)
    - Morgan, Robin (Box P/P8)
    - Mullins, Sandy (Box P/P8)
    - Murray and Abramson - U.C.L.A. (Box P/P8)
    - Myerson, Bess (Box P/P8)
    - Napolin, Leah (Box P/P8)
    - Natale, Kathryn (Box P/P8)
    - Neiderbach, Shelley (Box P/P8)
    - Newfield, Jack (Box P/P8)
    - Nicholson, Joan (Box P/P8)
    - Nicol, Dr. Davidson (Box P/P8)
    - Nicol, Marjorie (Box P/P8)
    - Niles, Janet (Box P/P8)
    - Novick, Lee (Box P/P8)
    - Norsiqian, Judy (Box P/P8)
    - Nussenbaum, Sonia (Box P/P8)
    - O'Leary, Jean (Box P/P8)
    - O'Neil, Peat Louisa (Box P/P8)
    - O'Reilly, Jane (Box P/P8)
    - O'Wyatt, Jane (Box P/P8)
    - Olsen, Tillie (Box P/P8)
    - Paley, Grace, 1976; 1978; 1986 (Box P/P8)
    - Pam, Eleanor (Box P/P8)
    - Patri, Jennifer (Box P/P8)
    - Pello, Marianne (Box P/P8)
    - Perry, Eleanor (Box P/P8)
    - Pildes, Judith (Box P/P8)
    - Pilpel, Harriet P. (Box P/P8)
    - Pisk, Panel (Box P/P8)
    - Pleck, Joseph (Box P/P8)
    - Pogrebin, Letty Cottin (Box P/P8)
    - Priesand, Rabbi Sally (Box P/P8)
    - Proto, Connie (Box P/P8)
    - Radl, Shirley (Box P/P8)
    - Ramano, Angela (Box P/P8)
    - Randell, Margaret (Box P/P8)
    - Raven, Arlene (Box P/P8)
    - Raymon, Paula (Box P/P8)
    - Reed, Evelyn (Box P/P8)
    - Reitz, Rosetta (Box P/P8)
    - Renninger, John (Box P/P8)
    - Rich, Adrienne (Box P/P8)
    - Robertson, Jean (Box P/P8)
    - Rosen, Steve (Box P/P8)
    - Rowe, Dr. Mary P. (Box P/P8)
    - Ruddo, Marcy (Box P/P8)
    - Rule, Jane (Box P/P8)
    - Rush, Anne Kent (Box P/P8)
    - Russ, Joanna (Box P/P8)
    - Russ, Rayomond (Box P/P8)
    - Russell, Diana (Box P/P8)
    - Sanchez, Carmen (Box P/P8)
    - Sanders, Marlene (Box P/P8)
    - Sandow, Danielle (Box P/P8)
    - Sands, Susan (Box P/P8)
    - Saxe, Susan (Box P/P8)
    - Scarf, Maggie (Box P/P8)
    - Scherfenberg, Craig (Box P/P8)
    - Schlesinger Library - Cambridge, Mass. (Box P/P8)
    - Schneiderman, David (Box P/P8)
    - Schneiderman, Stuart (Box P/P8)
    - Schotz, Myra (Box P/P8)
    - Schwab, Charlotte (Box P/P8)
    - Scopetta, Nick and Susan (Box P/P8)
    - Seaman, Barbara (Box P/P8)
    - Seiden, Anne (Box P/P8)
    - Seilder-Feller, Rabbi Chaim (Box P/P8)
    - Seigman, Rabbi Henry (Box P/P8)
    - Seligman & Collier - James Seligman - Agent - Basic Books (Box P/P8)
    - Shalala, Donna (Box P/P8)
    - Shapiro, Esther (Box P/P8)
    - Shapiro, Selma (Box P/P8)
    - Sheehy, Gail (Box P/P8)
    - Shear, Marie (Box P/P8)
    - Shields, Mary Lou (Box P/P8)
    - Shulman, Alix (Box P/P8)
    - Shulman, Grace (Box P/P8)
    - Singerman, Jessie (Box P/P8)
    - Singh, Nalini (Box P/P8)
    - Sisson, Jane - WCET. - T.V. (Box P/P8)
    - Skaife, Adrey M. (Box P/P8)
    - Sobel, Maxine (Box P/P8)
    - Sontag, Susan (Box P/P8)
    - Sorscher, Allen (Box P/P8)
    - Snodgerass, Jon (Box P/P8)
    - Stein, Deborah Susan Lea (Box P/P8)
    - Steinberg, Harry (Box P/P8)
    - Steinem, Gloria (Box P/P8)
    - Strauss, Walter (Box P/P8)
    - Sugarman, Mrs. C. (Box P/P8)
    - Swannack, Cheryl (Box P/P8)
    - Swinton, Pat - Shoshana (Box P/P8)
    - Tangri, Sandra (Box P/P8)
    - Tarzi, Wahid (Box P/P8)
    - Thaler, Pat (Box P/P8)
    - Thrush, Robin (Box P/P8)
    - Trahey, Jane (Box P/P8)
    - Trueman (Box P/P8)
    - Turkel (Box P/P8)
    - Verlaine, Jane (Box P/P8)
    - Virga, Vincent (Box P/P8)
    - Virginia Woolfe House (Box P/P8)
    - Vivas, Marta Elvia (Box P/P8)
    - Vogel Kathleen (Box P/P8)
    - Wagshal, Peter (Box P/P8)
    - Walker, Gerald (Box P/P8)
    - Walker, Lenore (Box P/P8)
    - Walker, Jinx (Box P/P8)
    - Wallace, Michelle (Box P/P8)
    - Walstedt, Joyce Jennings (Box P/P8)
    - Waskow, Arthur (Box P/P8)
    - Weideger, Paula (Box P/P8)
    - Weinberg, Beryl (Box P/P8)
    - Weisburg, Dr. Herbert (Box P/P8)
    - Weiss, Vivian (Box P/P8)
    - Weisstein, Naomi (Box P/P8)
    - Willadsen, Jytle, Brigid Peterson (Box P/P8)
    - Willis, Ellen (Box P/P8)
    - Windstone, Shebar (Box P/P8)
    - Withers, Rosamund (Box P/P8)
    - Wittig, Monique (Box P/P8)
    - Woesner, Mary (Box P/P8)
    - Wolf, Daniel (Box P/P8)
    - Wood Schnitzer, Shirley (Box P/P8)
    - Yankowitz, Susan (Box P/P8)
    - Yaseen, Ginny (Box P/P8)
    - Yglesias, Helen (Box P/P8)
    - Zabitz, Gerri - Halstead Press (Box P/P8)
    - Zion, Sydney (Box P/P8)
    - Zuckerman, Barbara (Box P/P8)
    - Zuckoff, Aviva (Box P/P8)
  - Personal and Financial Papers subseries, 1970s-1980s
    The Personal and Financial Papers Subseries, 1970s-1980s, documents Chesler's business concerns, personal and professional expenses, and personal responsibilities.
    - Accountant, 1974 (Box P/P8)
    - Accountant - Gissen, Herbert (Box P/P8)
    - Bibliography (Box P/P8)
    - Car Insurance - 1980 (Box P/P8)
    - Chemical Bank (Box P/P8)
    - Child Care (2 folders) (Box P/P8)
    - Child Care/ Daycare - Brooklyn, 1980 (Box P/P8)
    - Child Care - Housekeepers, 1980 (Box P/P8)
    - Child Care - Irish Women, 1980 (Box P/P8)
    - Chiropractor (Box P/P8)
    - Christmas Cards, 1979 (Box P/P8)
    - Curriculum Vitae - Master, 1979 (Box P/P8)
    - Consumer Plans (Box P/P8)
    - Cosman Diet (Box P/P9)
    - Credit Cards (Box P/P9)
    - Diets (Box P/P9)
    - Dogerty - Home Repairs (Box P/P9)
    - Domestic Routine Instructions (Box P/P9)
    - Dun & Bradstreet Co, Inc. (Box P/P9)
    - Employees - 1980-'81 (Box P/P9)
    - English Women (Box P/P9)
    - GHI Claims - 1979 (Box P/P9)
    - Graduate Students (Box P/P9)
    - Greater N.Y. Savings (Box P/P9)
    - Health Clubs (Box P/P9)
    - Health Clubs - Yoga, etc. (Box P/P9)
    - Health Collectives (Box P/P9)
    - Health Herbs - WELDA, Inc. (Box P/P9)
    - Health Plans - 1979 (Box P/P9)
    - Health Spa (Box P/P9)
    - Hebrew Schools (Box P/P9)
    - Hotels (Box P/P9)
    - House (Box P/P9)
    - Household Appliances (Box P/P9)
    - IBM - Typewriter (general) (Box P/P9)
    - Income Tax, 1972 (Box P/P9)
    - Income Tax, 1973 (Box P/P9)
    - Insurance (Box P/P9)
    - Insurance - Annuity/ C.U.N.Y. (Box P/P9)
    - Insurance - Life (Plans) (Box P/P9)
    - Irish-English Women (Box P/P9)
    - Irish-English Women - Unsuitable (Box P/P9)
    - Irish Women - 1980 -Questionnaire Response (Box P/P9)
    - IRS with Gissen, 1972 pending (Box P/P9)
    - Job Possibilities, 1978 (Box P/P9)
    - Jury Duty - 1980 (Box P/P9)
    - Klinger (Box P/P9)
    - Kroll Stationers, Inc. (Box P/P9)
    - Lawyers (Box P/P9)
    - Lease - Apt. Yoo - W.E.A. (Box P/P9)
    - Legal - Psychiatric (Box P/P9)
    - Life Insurance (Box P/P9)
    - Life Insurance - 1980 (Box P/P9)
    - Lordly & Dame, Inc. (Box P/P9)
    - Maine - 1979 -summer (Box P/P9)
    - MasterCharge (Box P/P9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box P/P9)
    - Motor Vehicle Bureau (Box P/P9)
    - New York State Employment Service (Box P/P9)
    - New York Telephone -- East Hampton (Box P/P9)
    - Office Info., 1980 (Box P/P9)
    - Olins Rent-a-Car (Box P/P9)
    - Painters -- 732A Carroll St. (Box P/P9)
    - Parking Violations (Box P/P9)
    - Park Slope Information -- Draft (Box P/P9)
    - Patient Bills (Box P/P9)
    - Phoenix (Box P/P9)
    - Phone Company (Box P/P9)
    - Postage Receipts (Box P/P9)
    - Practice Announcements (Box P/P9)
    - Recordophone (Box P/P9)
    - Renovation - Kudler (Box P/P9)
    - Reprints (Box P/P9)
    - Requests (Box P/P9)
    - Requests Literary, 1978 (Box P/P9)
    - Requests - impossible (Box P/P9)
    - Resorts (Box P/P9)
    - Retirement Plan (Box P/P9)
    - Schedule, 1979 (Box P/P9)
    - Schedules (Box P/P9)
    - Seder (Box P/P9)
    - Services (Box P/P9)
    - Social Security (Box P/P9)
    - Stationary Master (Box P/P9)
    - State License Info. - Psychology (Box P/P9)
    - Student Interns (Box P/P9)
    - Sublet --1979, Fall (Box P/P9)
    - Sublet -- 1980, Summer (Box P/P9)
    - Tape Recorders (Box P/P9)
    - Taxi Receipts (Box P/P9)
    - Taylor Management (Box P/P9)
    - Teaching Adjuncts (Box P/P9)
    - Telephone Company (Box P/P9)
    - Telephone Harassment, 1980 (Box P/P9)
    - Tenants Assoc. -- West End Ave. (Box P/P9)
    - TIAA (Box P/P9)
    - Travel (Box P/P9)
    - Travel Charter (Box P/P9)
    - Typewriter (Box P/P9)
    - Vitamins (Box P/P9)
    - Weston --1979, Summer (Box P/P9)
  - Correspondence subseries, 1970s-1980s
    The correspondence found in this subseries is chiefly professional, relating to Chesler's publishing efforts, promotion for her books, and organizations supported by Chesler or in which she had an interest. This subseries also includes some royalty statements and other miscellaneous financial materials related to several of Chesler's books. Material is arranged in alphabetical order according to Chesler's original folder titles.
    - About Men - Potential Blurbers (Box P/P9)
    - About Men - Quotes - In. (1) (Box P/P9)
    - About Men - Quotes - In. (2) (Box P/P9)
    - Agent - Abels Corresp. - Money and Men Books, 1974 (Box P/P9)
    - Benefit Mailing List, 1972, March (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - About Men - Post-pub. Comments (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Dias - 1977 (Italy) (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Editions Payot (Paris, France) (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Enaudi Editions (Italy - W&M) (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Forthcoming Venture (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Mohr Books - 1977 (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Rowohlt - 1977 - Royalties (Germany) (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Simon & Schuster (Box P/P9)
    - Book Business - Stein Books (Germany) (Box P/P9)
    - Boston, Daly Forum for promotion (Box P/P9)
    - California Contacts (Box P/P9)
    - Chile (Box P/P9)
    - Conferences, 1974-1975 (Box P/P9)
    - Consultations, 1975 (Box P/P9)
    - Contacts (Box P/P9)
    - Contacts - Freud and Feminism (Box P/P9)
    - Chrysalis, 1978-1979 (Box P/P9)
    - Foreign Publishers - Tax Exemption Forms (Box P/P10)
    - Goodman - General Corresp. 1974 (Box P/P10)
    - Holt Rinheart & Winston (Lerman) (Box P/P10)
    - Legal Hassles - Bantam/Emily Goodman (Box P/P10)
    - Letters from women (Box P/P10)
    - Lindisfarne (Box P/P10)
    - Lovers and Warriors - Bantam (Box P/P10)
    - Lovers and Warriors - Morrow (Box P/P10)
    - Lovers and Warriors - David Lubell, 1976 (Box P/P10)
    - Lovers and Warriors - Financial Correspondence, 1974 (Box P/P10)
    - Lovers and Warriors - Pictures (Box P/P10)
    - MABAT - Middle East Alternative Media Project (Box P/P10)
    - MacDowell Colony (Box P/P10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box P/P10)
    - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood (Box P/P10)
    - Morrow - Summer, 1975 (Box P/P10)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box P/P10)
    - Publicity - Bantam (Box P/P10)
    - Publishing - Miscellaneous (Box P/P10)
    - Publishing Requests, 1978 (Box P/P10)
    - Publishing Track Record, 1980 (Box P/P10)
    - Quest: A Feminist Quarterly (Box P/P10)
    - Quotes (Box P/P10)
    - Quotes - About Men (Box P/P10)
    - Requests for Quotes - About Men (Box P/P10)
    - Rosenberg Case (Box P/P10)
    - Royalties - Basic Books (Box P/P10)
    - Royalties - Doubleday/Avon (Box P/P10)
    - Royalties in France (Box P/P10)
    - Royalties - Rowohlt, 1977 (Box P/P10)
    - Royalties - Women Money and Power (Box P/P10)
    - Safran, Sheri - Publicist (Box P/P10)
    - Seligman, James - Literary Agent (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Contract, 1978 (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Contract, 1979 (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Foreign Requests (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Foreign Sales (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Miscellaneous (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Royalties (Box P/P10)
    - Women & Madness - Sweden (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Bantam Correspondence, 1977 (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Carol Hill, Editor at Morrow (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Letters to Ms. Magazine (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Lubell, David, esq., 1976 (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Lubell - Meetings, 1975 (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Morrow, Fall/Winter 1975 (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Morrow, 1976 (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Morrow lists (Box P/P10)
    - Women, Money & Power - Quotes (Box P/P10)
  - Invitations subseries, 1979-1992
    The Invitations Subseries, 1979-1992, documents Chesler's support of the arts as well as her involvement in feminist, environmental, and political causes. The wide range of invitations that she received include events such as art openings, musical and theatre performances, book signings, and feminist and political fund raising events and protests. The series is arranged in chronological order.
    - 1979, Jan. - 1981, Mar. (14 folders) (Box P/P11)
    - 1981, Apr.- 1983, Feb. (18 folders) (Box P/P12)
    - 1983, Mar. - 1985, Mar. (19 folders) (Box P/P13)
    - 1985, Apr. - 1986, Sept. (15 folders) (Box P/P14)
    - 1986, Oct. - 1988, Mar. (16 folders) (Box P/P15)
    - 1988, Apr. - 1989, Oct. (15 folders) (Box P/P16)
    - 1989, Oct. - 1992, Dec. (16 folders) (Box P/P17)
- International Committee for Women of the Wall Series, 1988-2001, 40 boxes
  The International Committee for Women of the Wall Series documents the work of the organization and the publication of the anthology Women of the Wall: Claiming Sacred Ground through the following subseries: Correspondence, Women of the Wall: Claiming Sacred Ground, Kotel Archive, Administrative Files, Media Files, and Audiocassettes. Original folder titles have been retained, though loose materials were labeled during processing.
  - Correspondence Subseries
    Primarily includes printed email, but also includes letters, faxes, and messages from listservs such as the Israeli Feminist Forum, Women's Tefillah Network, and Masorti: Torah and News from the Masorti Movement. Arranged in approximate chronological order.
    - 1989 (Box WOW1)
    - 1990 (Box WOW1)
    - 1991 (Box WOW1)
    - 1992 (Box WOW1)
    - 1993 (Box WOW1)
    - 1994 (Box WOW1-2)
    - 1995 (Box WOW2-6)
    - 1996 (Box WOW6-10)
    - 1997 (Box WOW10-13)
    - 1998 (Box WOW13-15)
    - 1999 (Box WOW15-17)
    - 2000 (Box WOW17-21)
    - 2001 (Box WOW21)
  - Women of the Wall: Claiming Sacred Ground Subseries
    Includes proposals, budgets, drafts, materials related to photo permissions, and research files for sections authored by Chesler, as well as correspondence with publishers, contributors, and co-editor Rivka Haut. Additional correspondence related to the book can also be found in the Correspondence Subseries. Also includes an interview with Anat Hoffman on audiocassette.
    - Women of the Wall: Claiming Sacred Ground Files (Box WOW22-27)
  - Kotel Archive Subseries